<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blue turtle blog</title>
    <link>https://blueturtle.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on blue turtle blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 10:18:27 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blueturtle.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>With Firefox69 Privacy Is the Default</title>
      <link>https://blueturtle.blog/news/with-firefox69-privacy-is-the-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 10:18:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueturtle.blog/news/with-firefox69-privacy-is-the-default/</guid>
      <description>Privacy is not an option in Firefox69 browser version. It is default by default. With the new release of the browser, these are the new features it prsents for its users:
 Block Third-Party Tracking Cookies (by default). Block Cryptominers (by default). Block Fingerprinting (on strict mode - you have to enable it,and I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how). Block autoplay video&amp;rsquo;s audio (by default).    Block Third-Party Tracking Cookies As mentioned in mozilla blog post, the new feature works behind-the-scenes to keep a company from forming a profile of you based on their tracking of your browsing behavior across websites — often without your knowledge or consent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images Native Lazy Loading and Its Polyfill</title>
      <link>https://blueturtle.blog/tutorials/images-native-lazy-loading-and-its-polyfill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 19:32:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueturtle.blog/tutorials/images-native-lazy-loading-and-its-polyfill/</guid>
      <description>What is Lazy loading Images, and videos consume a huge amount of data, and affects web performances. If your web page contains many images (or videos), it is true that some -if not many- of them are out of viewport. The normal behaviour of any browser is to load all images during the web page loading which may slow loading time.
Lazy loading is used to defer images loading until it is about to enter the viewport, and only load the ones that are displayed once the web page loads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Use Material-UI Icons With Super Ease</title>
      <link>https://blueturtle.blog/news/now-use-material-ui-icons-with-super-ease/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 10:19:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueturtle.blog/news/now-use-material-ui-icons-with-super-ease/</guid>
      <description>Instead of searching for icons in Material icons, and then trying to figure out what the required icon component name would look like, now you can directly search for any icon among 1,000+ official Material icons converted to svg icon components.
  Wondering how you can use the Material Design icons?
We are happy to unveil our new icons search directly built in the documentation 🔍✨.https://t.co/RoWxQ7Tib3 pic.twitter.com/k5yCMIC7xt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We Write &lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt; ?</title>
      <link>https://blueturtle.blog/articles/why-we-write-doctype-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 01:13:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueturtle.blog/articles/why-we-write-doctype-html/</guid>
      <description>Yes, this is for the absolute beginner, and also for those non-beginners who forgot. I am going to look back behinds and re-discover things we take as granted by asking &amp;ldquo;WHAT&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;WHY&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;HOW&amp;rdquo;.
  &amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&amp;#34;en&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;! DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; is the first html tag written at the beginning of any html file. It is not an element and doesn&amp;rsquo;t has content or closing tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let, Const, and ... Var</title>
      <link>https://blueturtle.blog/articles/let-const-and-...-var/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 14:20:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueturtle.blog/articles/let-const-and-...-var/</guid>
      <description>ES6 has introduced some new syntax features. One of them was key words const, and let to declare variables. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about why they are preferred over var.
  Scope🔭 var has a function scope. This means it is accessible anywhere in the function it is defined inside. See this example:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10  function buyHerChocolate(onDiet) { if (onDiet) { var decision = &amp;#34;Don&amp;#39;t do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Trap Focus Inside a Modal</title>
      <link>https://blueturtle.blog/tutorials/how-to-trap-focus-inside-a-modal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 13:04:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blueturtle.blog/tutorials/how-to-trap-focus-inside-a-modal/</guid>
      <description>Trapping focus is one of the important issues concerningaccessibility. In case of assistive technology (like screen readers)users, or keyboard users,trapping focus is a must.
We are going to talk about How to Trap Focus inside of a modal as long as it is open and transfer focus to the rest of page once it is closed.
  Let’s see what we have here.
Hint: If you only want the code snippet, just go to &amp;ldquo;Trap Focus Method&amp;rdquo; section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>